

Curriculum Vitae

behnazeslami30@gmail.com

 $\sim$ 

in

8

B. Eslami **B.** Eslami

B. Eslami behnazeslami30

#### **Profile**

Graduated with a master's degree in Information Technology with several published articles in reputable journals and conferences; fluent in English and proficient in technical tools; with more than ten years of work and research experience in Programming, Artifitial Inteligence, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Deep Learning or related research areas.

#### **Education**

## M.Sc. in Information Technology Engineering

2016 - 2018

Islamic Azad University Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran

GPA: 4.0/4.0

Thesis Title: "Text mining method for discovering associations between diseases and drugs based on biomedical documents" (Grade: 18.25/20)

Supervisor: Dr. Mehdi Habibzadeh Motlagh

# B.Sc. in Computer (Hardware) Engineering

2006 - 2010

**Image Processing** 

Qazvin Islamic Azad University, Qazvin, Iran GPA: 3.17/4.0 (Last Two Years GPA: 3.83/4.0)

Final Project Title: "Design and implementation of a device used to estimate the distance between cities by AVR microcontroller" (Grade: 20/20)

Supervisor: Dr. Hamidreza Rashidy Kanan

#### **Research Interests**

- Artifitial Intelligence
- **Machine Learning**
- **Deep Learning**
- Natural Language Processing

- **Data Analysis**
- Information Retrieval

# **Publications**

# **Journal Articles:**

- Behnaz Eslami, Zahra Rezaei, Mehdi Habibzadeh Motlagh, Majid Fouladian, Hossein Ebrahimpour-Komleh. "Using Deep Learning Methods for Discovering Associations between Drugs and Side Effects Based on Topic Modeling in Social Network." Soc. Netw. Anal. Min. 10, 33 (2020). (Link)
- 2. Zahra Rezaei, Hossein Ebrahimpour-Komleh, Behnaz Eslami, Ramyar Chavoshinejad, Mehdi Totonchi. "Adverse Drug Reaction Detection in Social Media by Deep Learning Methods." Cell J. 2020;22(3):319-324. doi:10.22074/cellj.2020.6615 (Link)
- Behnaz Eslami, Mehdi Habibzadeh Motlagh, Zahra Rezaei, Mohammad Eslami, Mohammad-Amin Amini. "Unsupervised Dynamic Topic Model for Extracting Adverse Drug Reaction from Health Forums". Applied Computer Science 16, no. 1 (Link)
- 4. Zahra Rezaei, Behnaz Eslami, Mohammad-Amin Amini, Mohammad Eslami. "Event Detection in Twitter by Deep Learning Classification and Multi-Label Clustering Virtual Backbone Formation." Evolutionary Intelligence. 2022 Mar 22:1-5. (Link)
- 5. Soroor Kalantari, Mohammad Soltani, Fardin Samadi Khoshmehr, Mehdi Maghbooli, Zahra Rezaei, Ali Abbasian Ardakani, Soheila Borji, Behzad Memari, Mohammad Bayat, Behnaz Eslami, Hamidreza Saligheh Rad. "Differential Diagnosis Among AD, MCI and Normal Aging Employing CBF-Maps Derived from ASL–MRI: An Artificial Intelligence Study." (Submited to RSNA Journal)

#### **Conference Presentations:**

1. Zahra Rezaei, Hossein Ebrahimpour-Komleh, Behnaz Eslami. "Event Detection in Twitter Big Data by Virtual Backbone Deep Learning." In High-Performance Computing and Big Data Analysis, Cham, 2019, pp. 18-31: Springer International Publishing. (Link)

CV - Behnaz Eslami

- Zahra Rezaei, Behnaz Eslami, Mohammad-Amini, Mohammad Eslami. "Hierarchical Three-module Method of Text Classification in Web Big Data." 6<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Web Research (ICWR), 2020, pp. 58-65 (Link)
- 3. Zahra Rezaei, **Behnaz Eslami**, Hossein Ebrahimpour-Komleh, Kaveh Daneshmand Jahromi. "Abnormality Detection in Musculoskeletal Radiographs by DenseNet and Inception-V3". *Iran J Radiol. 2019; 16(Special Issue):e99144.* (Link)
- 4. Mohammad Abbasi, **Behnaz Eslami**, Zahra Rezaei. "Brain Tumor Classification Using Deep Learning Methods." *Iran J Radiol. 2019*; *16(Special Issue):e99160* (Link)

#### **Book:**

1. Zahra Rezaei, **Behnaz Eslami**. "A Method for Plotting Disease Drug Analysis and Its Complications by Combining Sources of Scientific Documents Using Deep Learning Method with Drug Repurposing: Case Study Metformin." *IntechOpen, Drug Development Life Cycle Chapter. September (2022).* 

# **Professional Experience**

#### Data Scientist and Web Service Specialist

2010 - Present

Implementing, Developing, and Supporting text mining projects:

- Semantic similarity project in textual documents
- Information Technology documents Topic Modeling project
- Intelligent legal systems using 15 intelligent modules

Analyzing data sets inorder to use feature engineering techniques for different projects Conducting Research about innovative methods in the field of AI and Deep Learning Implementing, Developing, and Managing Web Services (SOAP and RestFull)

Information Technology Organization of IRAN (Ministry of ICT). Tehran, Iran

Data Scientist 2017 - 2021

- Extracting topics from medical papers by using Topic Modelling methods.
- Identifying the diseases and drugs Named Recognition Entity (NER) among PubMed papers by using BERT model.
- Drug Repurposing through data integration PubMed Case Study Metformin by using BERT model.
- Implementing a Q/A system for Qovid-19 through PubMed papers.
- Studying and using deep learning classification methods such as CNN, HAN, and FastText for classifying any textual documents (All kind of biomedical documents)
- Implementing a web interface for in-house data analysis pipeline whole-exome sequencing

Royan Institute. Tehran, Iran

■ Instructor June 2021

 Data Science of Business Course in Post MBA Program (Applied Machine Learning in Practice)

Industrial Management Institute, Tehran, Iran

#### Lecturer

Introduction to Data Science and its Applications

February 2021

Mazandaran University of Science and Technology, Mazandaran, Iran

November 2019

• First International Meeting on Artifitial Intelligence in Medical Imaging

National Brain Mapping Lab, Tehran, Iran

#### **Technical Skills**

Linux (CentOS, Ubuntu)

Python Programming

Java Programming

Scrapy & Beautiful Soap

Pandas and Numpy

Scipy & SciKit-Learn	TensorFlow	
Matplotlib, Seaborn, and Plotly	NLTK & Genism	
BERT	Keras	

## Language competence

Persian (Native), English (Fluent)

IELTS Academic:

Overall Score: 6.5 (2022/08/20)

## **Selected Courses and Projects**

Intelligent Decision Support Systems20/20Computer Architecture20/20Supply Chain Management20/20Digital Marketing20/20Advanced Engineering Topics in E-Commerce19.5/20Multimedia Systems17.5/20Algorithm Design16/20

#### **Selected Projects:**

- Intelligent module to recognize specific phrases including numbers, people, date, specific strings with pattern, and people (Men/Women) with Regular Expression and Named Entity Recognition (NER) techniques in textual documents
- The news classification system of a website containing ten different categories of news
- The bone age detection system
- Differential diagnostic aid system in hepatocellular carcinoma
- ASL MRI in Demantia

#### **Honors and Awards**

- Patent entitled "Alzheimer's Disease Imaging Diagnostic System Based on Emission Tensor Imaging (DTI)" In Inquiry at the Intellectual Property Center of the State Property Registry
- Reviewr in Journal of "Medical & biological engineering & computing"
   ORCID URL: https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7205-1331

### **Actitivie and Interests**

- Colored pencile drawing and Oil Painting
- Listening to Music
- Playing Tennis

#### **Certifications**

- Introduction to Machine Learning in Production, Deep Learning. Al, Coursera (October 2022)
- Python Programming Language (Basic and Advanced), Sematec School Tehran, Iran (60 hours)
- Certificate of Presentation, presented a paper titled "Hierarchical Three-module Method of Text Classification in Web Big Data." *At the 6<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Web Research*, *11 June 2020*.
- Certificate of Presentation, presented a paper titled "Identification and Classification of Adverse Drug Reaction in Social Networks by Using Deep Learning Methods in Text Mining." At the 6<sup>th</sup> Iranian Congress on Electrical and Computer Engineering with an applied perspective on new energies, 2 May 2019. Tehran, Iran.
- Certificate of Presentation, presented a paper titled "Extracting the Relationship between Disease and Side Effects of Drugs Topic Modeling Approach by Referring to Medical Texts in Social Networks." At the 4<sup>th</sup> National Conference on Technology in Electrical and Computer Engineering, 27 December 2018. Tehran, Iran.
- Oracle WebLogic Server 12c: Administration I Ed 2, September 2016 (15 hours) *Oracle University Training Class, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.*
- Oracle Service Bus 12c: System Admin, Design & Integrate Accel Ed 1, September 2016 (15 hours) Oracle University Training Class, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.

Data Science Instructor, Mehdi Habibzadeh Motlagh(Link) mehdi.habibzadehmotlagh@mcgill.ca McGill University, Montréal, Québec, Canada Data Science Consultant, z.rezaei@itrc.ac.ir Zahra Rezaei(Link) Iran Telecommunication Research Center Department of Electrical Engineering, Islamic Azad University Saveh Branch, Saveh, Iran Adjunct Professor of majidfouladian@gmail.com Majid Fouladian(Link) Electrical and Computer Engineering, Islamic Azad University Science and Research Branch, Tehran,

Iran